la
Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep.
Brother James. Yes, sir. And God spoke
all these words saying, "I am the Lord
thy God, which have brought thee out of
the land of Egypt out of the house of
bondage. Thou shall have no other gods
before me. Thou shall not make unto thee
any graven image or any likeness of
anything that is in heaven above or that
is in the earth beneath or that is in
the water under the earth. Thou shall
not bow down thyself to them nor serve
them, for I the Lord thy God am a
jealous God, visiting the iniquity of
the fathers upon the children unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me. And showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shall not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain, for
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shall
not do any work, thou nor thy son nor
thy daughter thy man servant nor thy
maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day, wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shall not kill. Thou shall
not commit adultery. Thou shall not
steal. Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shall
not covet thy neighbor's wife nor his
man servant nor his maid servant nor his
ox nor his ass nor anything that is thy
neighbor's. I read Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen. Amen.
So, here on question and answer you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. Let me introduce to
you the family that's on the panel this
evening. We got brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Jerome.
Peace and peace.
Brother Julius.
You muted, Julius.
Good evening, everybody.
Brother James. Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening. Brother Sean.
Good evening.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. What is our first
question of
the program?
Yes, uh there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Zion
wants to know where he can show that you
don't have to wear fringes anymore.
All right. Zion would like to know where
is it in the pages of the book that you
don't have to wear fringes anymore.
Guest caller.
Yes, well I'll tell you.
This is all about understanding.
And it's about keeping
the commandments.
Yep. And what y'all is doing with
fringes and and what and the people
running around here all worried about
wearing fringes and and and having
something that they called as our
culture, which you can't read in the
Bible. Not our culture.
Fringes have one thing and one thing
only, one reason only that they were
supposed to be worn.
And that's to remind them to keep God's
commandments. And nobody and the people
that talk about that never bothered to
go and read the reason why.
So,
I'm going to give a little uh uh uh uh
uh
a little mini
uh uh
lesson on fringes.
Because if you ain't got no
understanding, then just like anything
else, you you you will practice it and
don't know why. So, let's find out why
we are uh uh fringes was introduced.
Let's go in the in Numbers the 15th
chapter. We going We going to read
pretty quick tonight because I got few
scriptures to go to. So, that's why I
want to lay this to rest. I'm tired of
it.
Numbers 15 and we going to read verses
32 to 40.
Okay. Numbers 15 verses 32 to 40 says,
"And while the children of Israel were
in the wilderness, they found a man that
gathered sticks upon the Sabbath day.
And they found And they that found him
gathering sticks brought him unto Moses
and Aaron and unto all the congregation.
And they put him in ward because it was
not declared what should be done to him.
And the Lord said unto Moses, "The man
shall be surely put to death.
And all the con- all the congregation
shall stone him with stones without the
camp.
And all the congregation brought him
without the camp and stoned him with
stones and he died as the Lord commanded
Moses."
Now, and the Lord saying here,
pay attention.
This man was
breaking the Sabbath day.
And the Lord had him stoned to death.
Because because the people didn't know
what to do with him, so they had him
stoned to death. That's because the
wages of sin is death. Now, keep
reading. Let's see when fringes come in.
Go ahead and the reason.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
"Speak unto the children of Israel and
bid them that they make them fringes in
their bo- in the borders of their
garments throughout their generations.
And that they put upon the fringe of the
borders a ribbon of blue.
And it shall be unto you for a fringe
that you may look upon it and remember
all the commandments of the Lord and do
them.
And that
>> look here. Look what it say.
Uh Did they introduce the fringes?
Introduced the fringes so they would
remind you
to keep God's commandments.
Keep reading till you get to 40.
And that ye seek not after your own
heart and your own eyes after which he
used to go a whoring.
That ye may remember and their and their
houses and all the men that appertained
unto Korah and all their I'm sorry.
So,
that they may remember and do all my
commandments and be holy unto your God."
Now, the only reason
that the fringes was introduced was to
remind you to keep God's commandments so
you wouldn't be stoned to death.
It didn't work.
So, the Lord added
animal sacrifice to keep from killing
men. So, let's go quickly to Leviticus
the fourth chapter.
And we going to read verses 1 through 6.
Then we going to skip.
Okay. Leviticus the fourth chapter
verses 1 through 6 says, "And the Lord
spake unto Moses, saying, 'Speak unto
the children of Israel, saying, If a
soul shall sin through ignorance against
any of the commandments of the Lord
concerning things which ought not to be
done and shall be done against any of
them, if the priest that is anointed do
sin according to the sin of the people,
then let him bring for for his sin which
he had sinned a young bullock without
blemish unto the Lord for a sin
offering.
And he shall bring the bullock unto the
door of the tabernacle of the
congregation before the Lord and shall
lay his hand upon the bullock's head and
kill the bullock before the Lord.
And the priest that is anointed shall
take of the bullock's blood and bring it
to the tabernacle of the congregation.
And the priest shall dip his finger in
the blood and sprinkle of the blood
seven times before the Lord before the
veil of the sanctuary.
So, now, we still dealing with sin.
If the fringes had worked, then you
wouldn't have had to kill the animals
because the wages of sin is death. And
what is sin? The transgression of the
law, or the breaking of the commandment.
Do now.
So, instead of killing the person that
committed the sin now, they're killing
animal in his place, and the priest
would sprinkle the blood. And what is
that supposed to do? Skip down and read
verse 20.
Verse 20 says, "And he shall do with the
bullock as he did with the bullock for a
sin offering. So shall he do with this.
And the priest shall make an atonement
for them. And it shall be forgiven
them."
Now, look. Now, that's under the old
covenant.
First the fringes, now the animal
sacrifice.
All about death. God trying to keep from
killing this man. It That didn't work
either.
How do I know?
Because the Lord had to come into
another
covenant with this man. Cuz the animal
sacrifice and the killing was under the
old testament. So, the Lord said, "Okay,
now
I've done gave them the fringes.
Stop them to remind them not to break my
law.
It didn't work.
So, I kill animals instead of them
when they break my law.
So, I got to come up with another way to
keep this guy from sinning. So, let's go
into Jeremiah 31
and we're going to read verses 31
uh from 31 to 30
Jeremiah 31 from 31 to 33.
Okay.
Jeremiah 31 says, and 31 and 31 says,
"Behold, the days come, saith the Lord,
that I will make a new covenant with the
house of Israel and with the house of
Judah.
Not according to the covenant that I
made with their fathers in the day that
I took them by the hand to bring them
out of the land of Egypt, which my
covenant they
That's when he had them in the
wilderness. He gave them the fringes,
then he gave them the animal sacrifice.
He said, "So, now I'm going to make a
new covenant, not according to that
one."
Because they still would break his laws.
So, what is he going to do with these
same laws? Go ahead.
"Which my covenant they break, although
I was an husband unto them, saith the
Lord. But this shall be the covenant
that I will make with the house of
Israel after those days, saith the Lord.
I will put my law in their inward parts
and write write it in their hearts, and
will be their God, and they shall be my
people."
Now, he said he's going to get his laws,
them same laws now.
The fringes didn't work.
Killing animals didn't work. So, I tell
you what I'm going to do. I'm going to
make a new covenant. I'm going to put
these laws into your inner parts. I'm
going to write them in your mind.
Now, let's go to Hebrews 8th chapter
and read verse 7 through 10.
Okay.
>> want to confirm this.
Hebrews 8:7 through 10 says, "For if
that first covenant had been faultless,
then should no place have been sought
for the second.
For finding fault with them, he saith,
'Behold, the days come, saith the Lord,
when I will make a new covenant with the
house of Israel and with the house of
Judah.
Not according to the covenant that I
made with their fathers in the day when
I took them by the hand to lead them out
of the land of Egypt, because they
continued not in my covenant, and I
regarded them not, saith the Lord.'"
So, now, that's why he made the new
covenant, cuz they still kept breaking
the law.
So, he said, "I'm going to make a new
one, and they didn't re- regard it." So,
now, he's going to take put his laws in
your inward part. Now, I want to show
you what happen if the laws are in your
mind.
Let's go and read 119th chapter Psalm
and verse 11.
Psalm 119 and verse 11. This what happen
if the law's in your mind.
Okay.
Psalm 119 and verse 11 says, "Thy word
have I hid in mine heart, that I might
not sin against thee."
See, the your heart is how about your
mind. So, he's going to go and put them
in your mind. So, if them laws are
present in your mind all the time, you
ain't going to sin. You know what
saying? He said nothing else to keep
talking about his law and sin, but he
have not mentioned the fringes no more.
So, now, if your mind ain't going to
remind you,
but then Paul was talking to some people
that tried to go was trying to
still deal with the law.
So, what did Paul say? Let's go into
Galatians, the third chapter.
We're going to read verses 1 and 2
first,
and then we're going to skip down to 17
and continue.
Okay.
Galatians You said Galatians 3:1-2 and 2
first, correct, sir?
Uh, that's correct. Okay. It says, "O
foolish Galatians, who have bewitched
you, that ye should not obey the truth,
before whose eyes Jesus Christ had been
evidently set forth, crucified among
you?
This
This only will I learn of you, receive
ye the Spirit by the works of the law,
or by the hearing of faith?"
Okay, now, that's by the hearing of the
word of God. Now, let's find out what
law is he talking about.
Get down and read verses 17 through 19.
It says, "And this I say, that the
covenant that was confirmed before of
God in Christ, the law, which was 430
years after, cannot disannul that, it
should make the promise of none effect.
For if the
For if the inheritance be of the law, it
is no more of promise, but God gave it
to Abraham by promise.
Wherefore then serveth the law?
It was added because of transgressions,
till the seed should come to whom the
promise was made, and it was ordained by
angels in the hand of a mediator.
Now, pay attention. Look at the pattern
here.
Things that was added because of
transgression.
Animal sacrifices was added because of
Because it couldn't help. The people
kept sinning. And now, let's go to
Hebrews the 10th chapter.
We going to read We going to read
Hebrews 10:1, then we going to skip down
and read 4 and 5, and we going to make
another skip.
Okay.
Hebrews 10:1 says, "For the law, having
a shadow of good things to come, and not
the very image of the things, can never
with those sacrifices, which they
offered year by year continually, make
the comers there unto perfect.
Now, that let us know that this is the
same law that was added because of
transgression. Transgression because the
people sinned. They broke his
commandments.
So, this is the law that was added.
And it could never remove sin. So now,
that had to bring Jesus on the scene.
Which
when he died, started a new covenant.
Skip down and read verse 4 and 5.
It says, "For it is not possible that
the blood of bulls and of goats should
take away sins. Wherefore, when he
cometh into the world, he saith,
'Sacrifice and offering, thou wouldest
not, but a body hast thou prepared me.'"
Now, let's see what he wanted to use
that what he needed a body for. Skip
down and read verse 10.
By the which will we are sanctified
through the offering of the body of
Jesus Christ once for all.
Just because we still couldn't stop
sinning. So, we needed a sin offering.
Animals couldn't help us, so Jesus came.
Skip down to verse 14, from 14 and read
and start until 18.
Okay. Verse 14 says, "For what For by
one offering he hath perfected forever
them that are sanctified.
Whereof the Holy Ghost also is a witness
to us, for after that he had said
before, 'This is the covenant that I
will make with them after those days,'
saith the Lord. 'I will put my laws into
their hearts, and in their minds will I
write them.
And their sins and iniquities will I
remember no more.'"
Now, where You notice You notice it's
all about the law, isn't it? Correct?
Yes.
I'm going to write them in their heart.
In your inner part, I'm going to write I
In other words, I'm going to put them in
your mind. You continue.
Now, where remission of these is, there
is no more offering for sin.
Uh-huh. Now, that's That's what
Remission of these is, there is no more
offering for sin. What verse was that?
That was verse 18, sir.
So now,
animal offering for sin.
And if you continue to sin, you going to
be in trouble. So now, the fringes was
added because of sin.
Animal sacrifice
was added because of sin.
Then the death of Jesus had to come to
start a new covenant.
Why? Because man continued to sin.
It is all that
simple. Boom.
And everything And And And And And just
and and and and just like I was saying
like his answer now, And everything, and
earlier now,
there's no more read that last that 18th
verse. There's what? Because of sin.
Now, where remission of these is, there
is no more offering for sin.
So now, there ain't no more offering for
sin. Everything that was added because
of sin was terminated. It was
discontinued.
Just like the animal sacrifice
Also, the fringes are discontinued.
There's one other thing that was added
because of sin.
And it was discontinued. Let's find it
out real quick. Let's go to Genesis the
2nd chapter.
And read the
uh verse 7, then we're going to skip
down.
Okay.
Genesis 2:7 says, "And the Lord God
formed man of the dust of the ground and
breathed into his nostrils the breath of
life, and man became living soul."
Now, let's see what God said to this
man. Skip down to verse 16 uh uh uh uh
to verse and read verse 16 and 15.
Okay, verse 16 says, "And the Lord God
>> a minute.
Mhm. Verse 16 and 17 rather. I'm sorry.
Okay.
Verse 16 says, "And the Lord God
commanded the man, saying, 'Of every
tree of the garden thou mayest freely
free mayest freely eat. But of the tree
of the knowledge of good and evil, thou
shalt not eat of it, for in the day that
thou eatest thereof, thou shalt surely
die.'"
Now, the Lord gave a commandment. Don't
do this, cuz the day you do it, you're
going to surely die. Let's see what man
did. Let's go to Genesis the 3rd
chapter.
And we're going to read verse 4 and 6. 4
to 6, and we're going to skip. Okay.
Genesis 3:4 says, "And the serpent said
unto the woman, 'Ye shall not surely
die.
For God doeth know that in the day ye
eat thereof, then your eyes shall be
opened, and ye shall be as gods, knowing
good and evil.'"
And when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food, and that it was pleasant
to the eyes, and a tree to be desired to
make one wise, she took of the fruit
thereof, and did eat, and gave also unto
her husband with her, and he did eat.
So now,
man obeyed the commandment then,
disobeyed the commandment then. So, what
did the Lord do? He did what he said. He
added death. Skip down to verse 17 and
read it.
And unto Adam he said, "Because thou has
hearkened unto the Lord, unto the voice
of thy wife, and has eaten of the tree
of which I commanded thee, saying, 'Thou
shalt not eat of it,' cursed is the
ground for thy sake, and sorrow shalt
thou eat of it all the days of thy
life."
Now, he told this man, "Because you did
it, cursed is the ground."
Do you see?
Cursed is it.
And you're going to eat all the days of
your life until what? Rick, skip down
and read verse 19.
"In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread till thou return unto the ground.
For out of it was thou taken, for dust
thou art, and unto dust shalt thou
return."
Now, look at it.
Man got stoned to death for breaking the
law.
God added fringes. Didn't work. So, he
had animal sacrifice.
Added.
Didn't work.
So, he terminated it.
Now,
go back to the beginning.
Adam and Eve sinned against God. So,
death was added.
And let's see what's going to happen to
death now. Let's go to 1 Corinthians the
15th chapter.
And we're going to read from verse 26 21
to 26.
1 Corinthians 15:21-26
says, "For since by man came death, by
man came also the resurrection of the
dead.
For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
But every man in his own order. Christ
the firstfruits, afterward they that are
Christ at his coming.
Then cometh the end, when he shall have
delivered up the kingdom to God, even
the Father, when he shall have put down
all rule and authority and power.
For he must reign till he has put all
enemies under his feet. The last enemy
that shall be destroyed is death.
Wait a minute.
Why was death added to the creation?
Because of sin, wasn't it?
Mhm.
>> Yes.
Why was the man put to death?
Sin. For picking up Why was uh uh
fringes added?
Because of sin, wasn't it? Mhm.
>> All right.
Well, when when was animal sacrifice
added?
Sin.
It was added because of sin.
Then Jesus came and he died for sin.
Everything that was added because of
sin, animal sacrifice, fringes, and
death
is going to be terminated.
So, the fringes are terminated
and animal sacrifice is terminated
when Jesus died on the cross
and started a new covenant.
And at the end of the millennium period
at the end of Jesus' rule
he going to finally terminate the last
thing the the thing uh which was the
first thing that was added because of
sin, which is death.
Fringes are not our
culture.
>> culture?
Fringes was added because of death like
animal sacrifice was added because of
death and just like death Because of
sin.
all the sin.
Sin, sin, and sin. The whole thing is
keeping the law.
And when you go and read the rest of the
book find out find me a whole lot of
places where friend where the Lord keep
telling you to wear these fringes.
Uh-uh. The reason you wear fringes is
because of
sin and it didn't work.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
>> somebody got
All right. So, hope somebody got plenty
understanding out of that and
write those scriptures down and feel
free to spread the word.
All right. Sister Deborah, our next
question.
Next question. Charlotte T says, "I
heard some teacher say it's okay to
vacation on a cruise during the Sabbath
as long as you congregate with your
family in your cabin and no one is
working for you. True?"
Vacationing on a cruise on the Sabbath
day, guest caller.
This one
will be held over until the Lord come
and you can ask him.
That's all I have All right.
We'll leave it there as we move on to
our next one.
Moving on. Carolyn Jenkins asks, "In
Luke 7:37
and 38, a woman anointed Jesus' feet. Is
it okay for a woman to anoint and pray
for someone?"
Is it okay for a woman to anoint and
pray for someone, Brother Jerome?
Uh it it depends because uh
if you consider James chapter 5 you
know, that that anointing that that
woman did concerning Jesus' feet ain't
the same as that James chapter 5. So, I
just want to make sure you understand
that, okay? But let's go read
um
the verses you gave
in the question.
Luke 7:37 and 38. Yeah. Mhm. It says
"And behold, a woman in the city which
was a sinner when she knew that Jesus
sat at meat in the Pharisee's house,
brought an alabaster box of ointment and
stood at his feet behind him weeping and
began to wash his feet with tears and
did wipe them with the hairs of her head
and kissed his feet and anointed them
with ointment." Yeah, so it ain't the
same as James chapter 5, okay?
Uh but this woman she she wanted the
Lord to bless her and she wanted the
Lord to forgive her.
And that's why she was there, okay? So,
uh
read that
44 through 48.
Mhm.
"And he turned to the woman and said
unto Simon, 'Seest thou this woman? I
entered into thine house, thou gavest me
no water for my feet. But she hath
washed my feet with tears and wiped them
with the hairs of her head.
Thou gavest me no kiss, but this woman,
since the time I came in, hath not
ceased to kiss my feet.
My head with oil thou didst not anoint,
but this woman hath anointed my feet
with ointment. Wherefore I say unto
thee, her sins, which are many, are
forgiven. For she loved much, but to
whom little is forgiven, the same loveth
little. Mhm.
And he said unto her, thy sins are
forgiven. Yeah. So, yeah, that's that's
not the same as that James chapter 5.
So, if you doing what this woman doing,
Jesus didn't say she was wrong for doing
that, but that is not James chapter 5.
That's all I got to say.
I'd say go and read
what the Lord said
when a person gets sick.
James 5 as Jerome would say. Okay.
Okay.
All right. James 5 and 13.
Yeah, James James 5 and 13 says, is any
among you afflicted? Let him pray. Is
any merry? Let him sing psalms. Is any
sick among you? Let him call for the
elders of the church, and let them pray
over him,
anointing him with oil in the name of
the Lord.
Now, I have not seen a female elder of
the church.
It speaks for itself.
Mhm. That's all I have.
All right. We'll leave it right there.
Next question.
Next question, Skywriter asks, what is
the difference between
judgment seat of Christ and white throne
judgment?
All right. Let's call it the difference
between the judgment seat of Christ and
the white throne judgment.
Well, the judgment seat of Christ is the
white throne judgment. He's right.
chapter
Read verses 22
and skip down and read verse 27.
What chapter was that again, sir? What
book was it?
chapter 5
I'm sorry, John chapter 5. Okay. 5th
chapter of John
John 5
Okay, John 5
Um, what verses again did you want to
read, sir?
22. Okay.
It says,
first or I'm sorry, John 5 and 22 says,
For the Father judges no man, but he
hath committed all judgment unto the
Son.
That all men should honor the Son, even
as they honor the Father.
He that honoreth not the Son honoreth
not the Father which has sent him.
Verily, verily, I say unto
Uh-huh.
Okay, 27 says,
and hath
given him authority to execute judgment
also, because he is the Son of man.
So, now,
all the judgment is going to be done by
Jesus.
Father ain't going to judge nobody.
Therefore,
the judgment seat of Christ is the white
throne judgment.
Mhm.
See?
That's all I have to say.
Sure. Even the termination of death.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Our next one.
Next one, Vertraya dot dot dot Israel
asks, in Revelations 2 verse 24, what
are the depths of Satan as they speak?
The depths of Satan, Julius.
The depths of Satan. Let's go to
uh Revelation the
second chapter.
Okay, I'm there.
And read that verse 24.
It says, But unto you I say, and unto
the rest in Thyatira, as many as have
not this doctrine, and which have not
known the depths of Satan, as they
speak, I will put upon you none other
burden.
Now, the depths of Satan the devil is
the deceptive vices that he use to
persuade and to deceive people.
Those are the depths of the devil. Let
me give you a perfect example. Let's go
to 2 Corinthians the 11th chapter.
2 Corinthians the 11th chapter, brother
James. Okay. We're going to pick it
going to pick up at verse 3, and then
we're going to skip to 13.
Okay.
Second Corinthians 11:3 says, Well,
we're going to read three and four. Go
ahead.
>> Okay. But I fear, lest by any means, as
the serpent beguiled Eve through his
subtlety, so your mind should be
corrupted from the simplicity that is in
Christ. So, he deceived the woman was
deceived. She took the doctrine to her
husband, and they both ate or they
listened to it. Verse four, go ahead.
For if he that cometh preacheth another
Jesus, whom we have [clears throat] whom
we have not preached, or if he receive
>> a false prophet. Go ahead.
Or if ye receive another spirit, which
ye have not received, or another gospel,
which ye have not accepted, ye might
bear bear with him. So, now, that mean
you don't agree with them, you challenge
it.
Somebody going to come, another
preacher, say the devil is a fallen
angel. That's that spirit. He going to
bring you
a different word of God, like he told
the woman, you shall not surely die, but
the Lord told them you shall surely die.
So, they listened to the and the
graveyard is full of dead people. Now,
skip down verse 13, and go ahead.
For such are false apostles, deceitful
workers, transforming themselves into
the apostles of Christ.
>> These are some of the devices,
the the the the ability to make it look
like God, sound like God, but it's
really a satanic devil. Continue.
And no marvel, for Satan himself is
transformed into an angel of light.
Go ahead.
Therefore, it is no great thing if he
minister if his ministers also be
transformed as the ministers of
righteousness, whose end shall be
according to their works. So, they're
going to end up in the lake of fire. But
the bottom line is, the depths of the
devil is the way that he use to deceive
people. He can use your mother, your
father, your husband, your wife, your
children, so your friends, any way
possible to deceive you and take you
away from the word of God. I hope that
help. Anybody else?
That's That's good, brother. And we hope
that they find the truth and stick with
it, cuz we sure bring it here. Yes, sir.
>> All right. Our next
Our next question.
Next question. Shaniqua or Cool Joe B.
asks, "When you apologize, but the other
person isn't ready to talk, you move on.
If months later they're ready to discuss
what happened, do you think it's still
okay to engage after having moved on?"
All right, Dre. I apologize, but they
ain't ready to talk. What you say,
brother?
If you If you apologize to somebody for
something that you did to them,
and the person
needs some time to process what was
done,
and it takes them a month or two later
to come back to want to have a
conversation,
should you talk? Why not?
Why not have a conversation about it if
they want to talk?
Even though you moved on,
they may have had to process and want to
talk about it, but let's Let's go to
Mark 11. We're going to read verses
uh
25 and 26.
Mark 11:25-26.
Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
Okay.
It says, "And when ye stand praying,
forgive if ye have ought against any,
that your Father also which is in heaven
may forgive you your trespasses. Mhm.
But if ye do not forgive, neither will
your Father which is in heaven forgive
your trespasses."
Now, you done something that you want to
apologize for, they didn't receive you,
you moved on, and now you asking should
you talk. Absolutely, you should talk
about it. And And forgive them for
needing time to want to talk to you.
They're your friends. Right? But let's
go to one other place. Let's go to
Matthew 5. We're going to read verses
uh 23
and 24. Matthew 5:23-24.
Mhm. Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
Therefore, if thou bring thy gift to the
altar, and there and and there
rememberest that thy brother has ought
against thee, leave there thy gift
before the altar, and go thy way.
First be reconciled to thy brother, and
then come and offer thy gift. So, the
brother want or the sister want to talk
about the all that they had?
Hey, give them time to talk about it.
Have the conversation. What I mean, even
if you all at the end of the day don't
agree, at least hear them out. That's
all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question with
a time check. Yes, next question. The
time is 8:10. Zion daughters want you to
share some light on 1 Corinthians 10:4.
Does Does spiritual drink means
righteousness?
Also, did Christ literally follow them?
All right, the spiritual drink here,
brother Julius.
The answer The answer Does spiritual
drink mean righteousness? No. The
spiritual drink is the living water or
the word of God. Let me give you an
example.
Let me give you an example. Let's go to
St. John the 4th chapter quickly,
uh brother James. St. John chapter 4.
This is about Jesus and the woman at the
well. St. John 4.
And picking up at verse 7 and then skip
to 10.
Okay. You can read the whole chapter on
your own, though. The whole chapter on
your own. St. John 7.
And uh
St. John 4.
>> I'm sorry, St. John 4.
Okay. St. John 4.
Verse 7 says, "There cometh a woman of
Samaria to draw water. Jesus saith unto
her, 'Give me to drink.'" Skip down to
verse 10 and 11.
Jesus answered and said unto her, "If
thou knewest the gift of God, and who it
is that saith to thee, 'Give me to
drink,' thou wouldest have answered of
him Ask I'm sorry, thou wouldest have
asked of him, and he would have given
thee living water." So, now that went
above her head because she's thinking
physical water that we drink. And he's
talking about the word of God that he
has to offer her. That's what this
spiritual drink really is. Continue.
The woman saith unto him, "Sir, thou has
nothing to draw with, and the well is
deep. From whence then has thou that
living water?" She's still thinking
physical water. Skip down to verse 13 to
15. Go ahead.
Jesus answered and said unto her,
"Whosoever drinketh of this water shall
thirst again." That's the water That's
the physical water that we all drink
every day, all the time. But he's But
look what he's saying now. Go ahead.
"But whosoever drinketh of the water
that I shall give him shall never
thirst. But that But the water that I
shall give him shall be in him a well of
water springing up into everlasting
life." Now, this water that I'mma give
you is going to give you eternal life.
Let's look at what that water is. St.
John the 6th chapter and one verse.
St. John 6.
And 63.
I think we got to cut right to the
chase. Go ahead.
"It is the spirit that quickeneth.
Uh-huh.
>> The flesh profiteth nothing. The words
that I speak unto you, they are spirit
and they are life." It's the word,
sisters and brothers. The word. You can
read the whole chapter, but I want this
right here.
Skip down then cuz his own disciples
didn't understand it. Go down to verse
68 and read it.
Then Simon Peter answered him, "Lord, to
whom shall we go? Uh-huh.
>> Thou has the words of eternal life."
That is the spiritual water that we all
have to get that's going to lead us the
word of God that's going to give us
eternal life through the keeping of his
commandments and obeying of his law
statutes. That's all I got.
And Julius, did Christ literally follow
them? Thank you for Thank you, sister.
Let's find out. And the answer is yes.
Let's go to Exodus the 13th chapter.
Thank you, sister Deborah.
Exodus
the 13th chapter.
Israel He sprung Israel out of Egypt
>> [clears throat]
>> and uh led them through the wilderness.
How did he do it? Exodus the 13th
chapter and let's read verse 21 and 22.
When you get it, go ahead. Exodus 13:21
and 22. Go ahead.
"And the Lord went before them by day in
a pillar The Lord The Lord Uh-huh.
went before them by day in a pillar of a
cloud to lead them the way, and by night
in a pillar of fire to give them light
to go by day and night. And by to go by
day and night? Man.
And go ahead.
He took not away the pillar of the cloud
by day, nor the pillar of pillar of fire
by night from before the people. So now,
as as we stated in the previous
question, they all drink of that
spiritual rock that followed them, and
that rock was Christ.
In 1 Corinthians 10:4.
I hope that helps.
Yeah, man. Then they say they saw the
God of Israel.
They saw him.
>> Yes, they did. Yeah.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Next one.
Next one. Melvin Natural Journey says,
"Can you tell me where does it say we
are to become God in the Bible?"
Brother Julius, we know it's there.
Where is it?
Well, let's go to the first place. Let's
go to Psalms the 82nd chapter where it
is written.
Psalm 82, Brother James.
>> [clears throat]
>> And let's pick it and let's look at what
David the who spoke by the mouth uh the
the Lord speak by the mouth of David.
Look what he said in verse one. Psalm 82
and 1. Go ahead.
God standeth in the congregation of the
mighty. He judgeth among the gods. He
judged among the what? The gods. He
don't told. So,
go ahead at verse six. Six to eight. Go
ahead.
I have said, "Ye are gods, and all of
you are children of the most high." But
what happened?
But ye shall die like men, and fall like
one of the princes. Uh-huh. Arise, O
God, judge the earth, for thou shalt
inherit all nations. And when Jesus come
back, and all of us who in the first
resurrection, we will be God, and we
will be judges.
Now, let's go to
uh St. John the 10th chapter.
That's the Old Testament. Let's go to
the New Testament, and the book said the
prophets are subject to the prophets.
St. John 10.
And when you get it,
Jesus contended with the scribes and
Pharisees. Look what he told them in
verse 34.
Jesus answered them, "Is it not written
in your law, I said, 'Ye are gods'?"
Now, continue.
"If he called them gods, unto whom the
word of God came, and the scripture
cannot be broken." That is huge.
Because he could
he said, "I'm the son of God." But the
Jews didn't believe him. And he put it
up in their face. He put their own word,
the word of God, which they supposed to
have known.
He said, "Is it not written what I said
in Psalm 82? Is it not written, 'I have
said that ye are gods'?"
And the scriptures cannot be broken. So,
we are going to be gods.
Now, my last place. Let How did that go
happen? 1 Corinthians the 15th chapter.
It's all here, sisters and brothers.
It's all here.
God for that.
Let's Let's get right to the cut to the
chase. How's it going to happen? Cuz
this mortal got to put on immortality.
Pick it up at verse 49, Brother James,
and read it.
And as we have borne the image of the
earthy, we shall also bear the image of
the heavenly. Uh-huh. Now, this Mhm. No,
go ahead. Go ahead. Read on through.
Now, this I say, brethren, that flesh
and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of
God. Neither doeth corruption in inherit
incorruption. Go ahead.
Behold, I show you a mystery. We shall
not all sleep, but we shall all be
changed. Everybody not going to be dead
when the Lord come, because the
righteous got to be changed. Read it.
In a moment, in the twinkling of an eye,
at the last trump, for the trumpet shall
sound, and the dead shall be raised
incorruptible, and we shall be changed.
Because we shall not all die, but we
shall all be changed. Go ahead.
For this corruptible must put on
incorruption, and this mortal must put
on immortality. God is a spirit being,
immortal.
And that's why the scriptures can says
that it cannot be broken, because it
must happen. Finish it, and we're done.
So, when this corruptible shall have put
on incorruption, and this mortal shall
have put on immortality, then shall be
brought to pass the saying that is
written, "Death is swallowed up in
victory."
Why Why death? Because he told you in
Psalm 87th chapter, you shall die like
men. Men die. So, when the Lord come and
like the guest caller said earlier and
do away with
with death, you got eternal life.
Hopefully on the right side of the
kingdom.
That's all I got.
And we know it's impossible for this God
to lie.
And in Revelation 20th chapter, he told
you you going to be judges.
All right. We'll go go to one more
place, guest caller.
Let's go to Philippians the second
chapter start reading at verse five.
Yes, sir.
Philippians
>> Philippians the second chapter verse
five says,
"Let this mind be in you, which was also
in Christ Jesus.
Who being in the
Pay attention. He said, "Let this mind
be in you." That's talking about us.
He's talking to Okay.
Yeah.
>> was also in Christ Jesus. Go ahead.
"Who being in the form of God, thought
it not robbery to be equal with God.
But look, the only way for you to be
equal with God is to be God. Isn't that
correct? That is right.
Case closed.
Praise the Lord.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Next one.
Next one. Sky Rider says, "If someone is
in a terrible marriage where there's
constant abuse and mistreatment,
can they divorce?"
Guest caller.
Go to 1 Corinthians the seventh chapter.
We're going to read from verse 12
through 15 because if somebody is
abusing somebody all the time, then that
mean that they are non-believer. Mhm.
Believing God, you ain't going to you
don't want to abuse nobody you love.
Go ahead and read it.
Okay. That is 1 Corinthians 7
starting at what verse again, sir?
Go and read from 12 to 15. Okay. It
says, verse 12 says, "But to the rest
speak I, not the Lord. If any brother
hath a wife that believeth not, and she
be pleased to dwell with him, let him
not put her away.
And the woman which hath an husband that
believeth not, and if he be pleased to
dwell with her, let her not leave him.
For the unbelieving husband is
sanctified by the wife, and the
unbelieving wife is sanctified by the
husband. Else were your children
unclean, but now are they holy."
"But if the unbelieving depart, let him
depart. A brother or a sister is not
under bondage in such cases, but God has
called us to peace."
Now, let you know if this unbelieving
person leave you,
and a lot of them leave you don't don't
don't mean leaving the house all the
time. If they beating on you all the
time and abusing you, then they left
you. Then you say God said sister
brother's not under bondage then.
But let's go to Malachi the second
chapter.
And we and we going to read from verse
13 to 16.
Okay. Malachi 2 verses 13
to 16 says,
"And this have ye done again, covering
the altar of the Lord with tears, with
weeping, and with crying out, insomuch
that he regardeth not the offering
anymore, or received it with goodwill at
your hand.
Yet ye say, 'Wherefore?' Because the
Lord has been witness between thee and
the wife of thy youth, against whom thou
has dealt treacherously.
Yet is she thy companion
Verse Yeah, he said, "You know, you
ain't even want to come You're always in
his face, 'Lord, forgive me. Lord, give
me this and give me that.' And ain't
nothing happening to positive, and
you're always up against it. And he
said, 'Why?'
Cuz the Lord don't hear you no more.
Why? He said, "Because he been witness
between
you and the wife of your youth." The
Lord is looking at this marriage. Go
ahead.
"Yet is she thy companion and the wife
of thy covenant.
And did not he make one?
Yet had he the residue of the spirit,
and wherefore one?
That he might seek a godly seed.
Therefore, take heed to your spirit, and
let none deal treacherously against the
wife of his youth."
I'm Go ahead. "For the Lord For the Lord
the God of Israel saith that he hated
putting away for one covereth violence
with his garment saith the Lord of host.
Therefore, take heed Mhm.
Finish it.
Take heed to your spirit that you deal
not treacherously.
The Lord hate uh violence.
And so if this person is beating on you
and abusing you, the Lord don't is a
understanding God.
They know that where he tell you you
have to stay there and take that cuz he
hate violence.
And they are non-believers.
If they are non-believers, if they going
to beat you, they may as well That's the
equivalent to leaving you. And Lord said
you are not under bondage in that in
such case.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Our next one.
Next one, bro asks us in Exodus 20 verse
12, "My elderly dad moved in with me
because he can't live alone or care for
himself anymore. If I refuse to take him
to Sunday church or allow anyone to take
him, am I dishonoring him?"
I wouldn't say that.
You know, you have some elderly people
been going to church
you know, for a long time they believe
there, but you can plant seeds and see
if you can encourage him to come to
church with you.
But um Exodus 20 and they asked about
that verse 12 that we read opening up,
James.
Read that.
Verse 12 says,
"Honor thy father and thy mother that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee."
So, that's what you asking question, but
like you said, you know, you don't want
to take him, but somebody else wants to
take him, then you just hey
stay out the way and plant some seeds.
See if maybe you can get him to join
you. You know, but uh totally denying
him the right to go and he may have been
going there his whole life.
I wouldn't suggest that.
And that's all I got.
All right. We'll go move on to our next
question.
Next one, daughter of light asks was
Noah Noah a Hebrew Israelite?
Jerome, Hebrew Israelite, Noah.
No. [clears throat]
Noah wasn't a Hebrew
Israelite. Um consider Jacob whose name
was changed to Israel. He wasn't even
born yet.
Mhm. And neither was Abraham
born yet. And the reason why Israelites
are even called Hebrews because they
trace back to Abraham. Um yeah, to
Abraham. But Abraham wasn't born yet,
neither was Jacob. So, no
uh
he he wasn't a Hebrew Israelite, okay? I
got a few verses I want to read though.
Uh 1 Corinthians I'm sorry. 1
Chronicles.
1 Chronicles.
And we're going to read verse 4 and then
we're going to skip to verse 24.
1 Chronicles what book?
I mean what number? What chapter?
>> 1 chapter. Okay, 1 chapter.
>> And read verse 4 and then skip to verse
24. Okay.
1 Chronicles 1 and 4 says, "Noah, Shem,
Ham, and Japheth."
And skip down to verse uh 24 read to 28.
Shem
Arphaxad, Shelah
Eber, Peleg, Reu Serug, Nahor, Terah
Abram the same is Abraham. Mhm. The sons
of Abraham, Isaac and Ishmael. And skip
down to verse 34.
And Abraham begat Isaac. The sons of
Isaac, Esau and Israel. Yeah, see these
guys didn't come around Abraham and
Jacob, they didn't come around till many
generations later.
So, no. He Abraham's not a Hebrew
Israelite.
That's all I got. Brother Brother
Cordell, I was asked that question
uh
out of town and I I said we looked what
what Noah was, read Luke 3 and he was
listed Yeah.
>> uh as one of the sons of God. Yeah,
that's what I meant to say. I said
Abraham, but I meant Noah. Thank you,
bro.
>> [laughter]
>> All right.
Okay.
Moving on to our next question.
Next one, Sharon Rowe wants you to
explain Haggai 2 verses 12 and 13.
Haggai 2
12 through 13. Need some light, brother
Dre. That's that book right after
Zephaniah.
Let's go there, brother James, and read
Haggai 2
12 and 13.
Before Zechariah.
It says
If one bear holy flesh in the skirt of
his garment, and with his skirt do touch
bread, or pottage, or wine, or oil, or
any meat, shall it be holy?
And the priest answered and said, "No."
Then said Haggai, "If one that is
unclean by a dead body touch any of
these things, shall it be unclean?" And
the priest answered and said, "It shall
be unclean."
So, both of these things, if you do
these, you'll be unclean. But, read
verse 14. Go ahead.
Then answered Haggai and said, "So is
this people, and so is this nation
before me, saith the Lord.
And so is every work of their hands, and
that they and that which they offer
there is unclean." So, everything that
this nation was doing was unclean, and
that's what Haggai is talking about.
He's showing these examples, he's asking
these questions, and then he goes on to
say "So is this people, and so is this
nation before me, saith the Lord. And so
is every work of their hands, that which
they offer there is unclean." That's all
it's saying. It's self-explanatory. Yep,
that's it.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question as time is ticking.
Yes, Glenn serious says in Psalms 46
verses 4 and 5, is this river the same
river mentioned in Ezekiel chapter 47?
All right. Psalms 46 verse 4 and 5.
Go there, James.
Read that. They want to know is this the
same river mentioned in Ezekiel 47.
Okay. Psalm 46 verses 4 and 5 says
There is a river, the streams whereof
shall shall make glad the city of God,
the holy place of the tabernacles of the
most high.
God is in the midst of her, she shall
not be moved. God shall help her in that
right early.
All right. Now, you can flip over to
Ezekiel
and
guest caller, take it from there. I know
we're not going to read the whole
chapter.
Okay. What verse in 47?
Um guest caller?
I don't feel no I don't see no reason in
in in reading it. That's talking about
the water that's coming out from under
the the house of God. And it
get
It
it it's
gets deep and deeper and it becomes a
river.
It heals.
And whatever doesn't heal, but as far as
I'm concerned, there ain't no scripture
that said these are the this is the
same. So, I don't see no reason to get
nothing in no big disputation on it.
All right. We'll go keep it moving to
our next one.
Next one, Daniel Wellington wants you
wants to know if you can use a microwave
on the Sabbath.
No. N O.
Let's go to Exodus 16.
Popular question, but the answer is no.
You can cook a chicken in a microwave.
And as we always say, brother Julius,
last word of that is oven, microwave
oven.
And you are cooking.
Yep. And that go the same thing for
those electric pots and all that stuff.
For one day, just treat it as though
it's holy, just like does says the Lord.
And it can be a blessing in it for you.
Let's go to that Exodus 16. And this is
what you do the day before so you don't
have to use the microwave oven.
Exodus 16 and 22. Go ahead, brother.
And it came to pass that on the sixth
day they gathered twice as much bread,
two omers for one man, and all the
rulers of the congregation came and told
Moses. Friday before it got dark,
gathered twice as much so they'd be
straight for the Sabbath day. Go ahead.
And he said unto them, "This is that
which the Lord has said.
Tomorrow is the rest of the holy Sabbath
unto the Lord.
>> ahead.
Yes.
Bake that which you will bake today and
seethe that which you will seethe and
that which remaineth overlay up for you
to be kept unto the morning. So,
anything you want to prepare, bake,
boil, whatever, do it before the Sabbath
kick in. Go ahead.
And they laid it up till the morning as
Moses bade and it did not stink. Neither
was there any worm therein.
Mhm.
And Moses said, "Eat that today, for
today is a Sabbath unto the Lord. Today
you shall not find it in the field."
All right.
Six days shall you gather it, but on the
seventh day, which is the Sabbath, in it
there shall be none.
Yep, there shall be none. And the Lord
said, "Gather it before the Sabbath
day." Well, let's see the hard-headed
people. Verse 27.
And it came to pass that there went out
some of the people on the seventh day
for to gather and they found none. What
the Lord say?
And the Lord said unto Moses, "How long
refuse you to keep my commandments and
my laws?" Because it was commandment and
the law that you rest on the Sabbath
day. So, you don't have to use your
microwave. Everything that you want to
eat, start preparing it the day before.
And then you'll be keeping the Lord's
Sabbath day. Remember the Lord said he
wants you to call that a pleasure on his
holy day, a Sabbath of delight and holy
unto the Lord. So, get accustomed to
doing it that way and you'll be obeying
the law of the Lord. That's all I got.
And we're going to move on to our next
question.
Next one. Thou says, "I'm trying to
understand the story of David and Nabal.
If David was the man being provisions
after offering protection
Nabal never asked for, why is Nabal
treated as the villain? And why does God
strike him dead when he didn't actually
do anything wrong?"
All right. Guess caller, Nabal and David
here.
You know what I said to God to ask this
question?
But, as soon as you see God, you ask him
why.
That's all I got to say.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next one.
Next one. Talitha
Rockwell says, "I have a close family
member that followed a bad doctrine for
over a year. Is it wrong to bring up
past issues when that individual has
already asked God for forgiveness and
joined IOG?"
What you say, Dre? What you say?
Absolutely is wrong.
Let's Let's go to Exodus I mean, Ezekiel
18.
Ezekiel 18 and read verses 20 and 21.
Ezekiel 18 and verse 20 and 21 says,
"The soul that sinneth, it shall die.
The son shall not bear the iniquity of
the father, neither shall the father
bear the iniquity of the son. The
righteousness of the righteous shall be
upon him and the wickedness of the
wicked shall be upon him." Go ahead.
>> But if the But if the wicked will turn
from all his sins that he had committed
and keep all thy all my statutes and do
that which is lawful and right, he shall
surely live. He shall not die. Now,
obviously this guy, whatever he was
into, he left.
And now he's at IOG and he's keeping the
word of God. Look at what God say about
this. Read the next verse. Go ahead.
"All his transgressions that he had
committed, they shall not be mentioned
unto him.
And his righteousness that he had done,
he shall live." So, if God don't mention
his transgressions
or what he used to do, why should you?
That's all I got.
Dre, yes, sir. Let the sun set on that
and be done.
All right. Moving on to our next one.
Yeah, she also asked, "Why is the reason
She also asked, "Is the reason why we
can't find Moses' body is because of
Jude 1
uh Jude 1 verse 9?"
All right. Moses' body.
Brother Julius.
Is the reason why we can't find Moses
body is because of Jude 1:9. What it
say?
Uh brother James.
It says,
"Yet Michael the Archangel, when
contending with the devil, he disputed
about the body of Moses. Dares not bring
against him a railing accusation, but
said, 'The Lord rebuke thee.'"
And your question is is the reason why
we can't find Moses body because of Jude
1:9. The answer is no.
I'm going to show you why the reason why
we can't find Moses body. Let's go to
Deuteronomy the 34th chapter.
Yep.
>> I'm there.
Deuteronomy 34.
Pick it up at verse 1.
And then we go skip.
Go ahead, James.
It says, "And Moses went up from the
plains of Moab unto the mountain of Nebo
to the top of Pisgah, that is over
against Jericho. And the Lord showed him
all the land of Gilead unto Dan."
Skip down to verse 4.
"And the Lord said unto him, 'This is
the land which I swore unto Abraham,
unto Isaac, and unto Jacob, saying, I
will give it unto thy seed. I have
caused thee to see it with thine eyes,
but thou shalt not go over thither.'"
Okay. Now,
here's your answer. Let's go.
Verse 5.
"So Moses the servant of the Lord died
there in the land of Moab according to
the word of the Lord." Go ahead. "And he
buried him in a valley in the land of
Moab against Beth-peor,
but no man knoweth of his sepulchre unto
this day." So, the reason why no you
can't find the body of Moses cuz God
buried him and God said that no man
knows where his body is until this day.
Has nothing to do with Jude 1:9.
That's all I got for you.
Okay.
Thank you for that. Let us move on.
Moving on. Name L has two questions. Uh
one, will there still be free will in
the Father's kingdom? And if so, two,
will people remember their loved ones
who are said to be burning for eternity?
All right. Free will in the Father's
kingdom, first one, Julius. Let's look
at what the Father's kingdom is. Matthew
the sixth chapter.
>> [clears throat]
>> Matthew chapter 6.
See, that's what's got us in trouble,
free will. The Lord told you in the in
the uh uh
uh in the garden.
He told And then he told you in Exodus
to keep his commandments.
Our mother and father blew it.
Because we made the wrong choice.
Matthew 6 and 33, go ahead and read.
It says,
"But seek ye first the kingdom of God
and his righteousness, and all these
things shall be added unto you." The
kingdom of God is righteousness.
That's the only thing you're going to
focus on. That's all you're going to be
dealing with is righteousness.
One more place. Romans the 14th chapter.
Romans chapter 14.
Will there be free will? Yeah, the will
to do right.
Those who are born of God cannot sin.
That's a choice.
Romans 14 and one verse, verse 17,
James. When you get it, read it.
It says,
"For the kingdom of God is not meat and
drink, but righteousness and peace and
joy in the Holy Ghost." So, that's what
the king That's what it's going to
That's what That is what's going to
exist in the Father's kingdom.
Peace, joy, righteousness.
And the lake of the lake of fire will
still be there
uh because the Lord said you're going to
go over and look at the people that have
sinned against
against uh uh
uh against him in the lake of fire. Has
nothing to do with your emotions.
They made their choice, you made your
choice.
Yep.
The answer is in the rich man. Yes, sir.
So, yeah. Everybody in the fire will not
be there by accident. Okay.
And will And will people be remember
will
will people remember that their loved
ones who are said to be burning for
eternity.
>> Every man is going to be judged
according to his works. You got you you
got the kingdom of God, you in there?
Your emotions don't count anymore. All
things that's in the kingdom of God is
righteousness.
That's flesh. That is flesh that's
talking and flesh that's thinking.
We didn't graduate from that. You will
be a spirit being.
Yes, caller. Hello.
Yeah, well, you know, they will know one
another because remember
Abraham
and the rich man was talking to one
another
and Lazarus was there
and they all knew one another.
Yep. Only difference is they said we
can't come to where you are and you
can't come to where we are. That's
right.
>> they're going to go
but they knew one another. So, if they
knew one another, then you going to know
your loved ones, too.
Yep.
>> And they going to know you.
And uh
also in in Matthew 17 at the
transfiguration, they saw Moses and you
know, Peter saw Moses and and and
Elijah.
You know, and they knew who they was.
Yeah.
Yep.
Yep. So, ain't in one place, you'll be
in the other. They have. All right.
That's for sure. Okay, we hope that
answered your question. Our next one.
Next one, Valencia asks, "What does it
mean, Aaron's rod that budded in Hebrews
9:4?"
Let's go to Hebrews 9 and 4.
What was the significance of Aaron's
budding rod?
Come on, James. 9:4.
Which had the golden censer in the ark
of the covenant overlaid round about
with gold, wherein was the golden pot
that had manna and Aaron's rod that
budded and the tables of the covenant.
Yes, caller. Aaron's rod budded.
Well, Aaron's rod budded because God is
showing who his priest is. Yep. So,
there was there was some people
complaining. Let's go to Numbers the
16th chapter.
We're going to read 1 to 3 first and
then we're going to skip down to 8 and
read to 11.
Okay.
Excuse me. Numbers 16
and start again at what scripture, sir?
What?
One.
>> Go from 1 to 3.
Okay. It says, "Now Korah, the son of
Izzhar, the son of Kohath, the son of
Levi, and Dathan and Abiram, the sons of
Eliab and On, the son of Peleth, sons of
Reuben, took men.
And they rose up before Moses with
certain of the children of Israel, 250
princes of the assembly, famous in
congregation, men of renown.
And they gathered themselves together
against Moses and against Aaron and said
unto them, 'Ye take too much upon you,
seeing all the congregation are holy,
every one of them, and the Lord is among
them. Wherefore then lift up yourselves
above the congregation of the Lord.'"
Now,
get down to verse 8 cuz the Lord was
listening to all of that. Verse 8 read
to 11.
Okay.
And Moses said unto Korah, "Hear, I pray
you, ye sons of Levi. Seemeth it but a
small thing unto you that the God of
Israel has separated you from the
congregation of Israel to bring you near
to himself to do the service of the
tabernacle of the Lord and to stand
before the congregation to minister unto
them.
And he hath brought thee near to him and
all thy brethren, the sons of Levi, with
thee. And seek ye the priesthood also?
For which cause both thou and all thy
company are gathered together against
the Lord. And what is Aaron that ye
murmur against him?"
So, now, the Lord
uh uh uh
the the the Levites, like Dathan and all
and Korah and all them guys, they was
trying to
uh uh say that they should be high
priests.
Yeah. But the Lord has chosen Aaron to
be high priest. So, this is how he did
that.
Now, let's go to Numbers the 17th
chapter and read 1 through 10.
Okay.
Numbers 17:1-10
says,
"And the Lord spake unto Moses saying,
"Speak unto the children of Israel and
take of every one of them a rod
according to the house of their fathers,
of all their princes according to the
house of their fathers, 12 rods. Write
thou every man's name upon his rod.
And thou shall write Aaron's name upon
the rod of Levi for one rod shall be for
the head of the house of their fathers.
And thou shall lay lay them up in the
tabernacle of the congregation before
the testimony where I will meet with
you.
And it shall come to pass that the man's
rod whom I shall choose shall blossom.
And I will make to cease from me the
murmurings of the children of Israel
whereby they murmur against you.
And Moses spake unto the children of
Israel and every one of their princes
gave him a rod a piece
for each prince one according to their
father's house, even 12 rods. And the
rod of Aaron was among their rods.
And Moses laid up the rods before the
Lord in the tabernacle of witness. And
it came to pass that on the morrow Moses
went into the tabernacle of witness and
behold the rod of Aaron for the house of
Levi was budded and brought forth buds
and bloom blossoms and yielded almonds.
And Moses brought out all the rods from
before the Lord unto all the children of
Israel and they looked and took every
man his rod. And the Lord said unto
Moses, "Bring Aaron's rod again before
the testimony to be kept for a token
against the rebels and thou shall quite
take away their murmurings from me that
they die not."
So, the reason Aaron's rod was there was
to remind
Israel
that God chose
Aaron and his seed to be the high
priest.
Yep.
That's all I had to say. That's right.
Shut the rebels up.
All right.
Yes, sir. Next question, sisters. Time
is a ticket when you having fun.
Yes, brother Brad asked, "Are there any
scriptures that talk about the time of
the year Jesus was born?
I try I tried to explain to people that
Christmas
has nothing to do with Jesus."
All right. Let's brother Jerome to do
some explanation also.
Well, let's look at some verses that
they try to use to prove what year Jesus
was born. Let's go to um Luke.
As you you can't prove it, but these are
verses they try to use to to prove it.
Okay?
Um Luke
chapter 1
and read verse 24 for me.
Okay. It says, "And after those days his
wife Elizabeth conceived and hid herself
five months saying, Okay, so this five
months, you know,
uh
they try to say well, that's the fifth
month of the year. It didn't say that.
This this
pretty much talking about the the five
months that she was
with child. Okay? Read verse 25 through
26.
Thus hath the Lord dealt with me in the
days wherein he looked on me to take
away my reproach among men.
And in the sixth month the angel Gabriel
was sent from God unto a city of Galilee
named Nazareth.
Okay. Once again, this not time about
you can't say this was the sixth month
of the year.
More than likely this was the sixth
month of her pregnancy.
Okay?
Elizabeth's pregnancy, all right? So,
uh
yeah, you can't use this to try to prove
that the Lord uh
what year the Lord was born. Uh
and they also try to use Matthew's the
second chapter. So, let's let's let's go
there right quick.
Matthew's the second chapter,
uh
dealing with Herod and when Jesus was
born. Okay?
Matthew's 2
uh verse 1 through 6. Okay.
Now, when Jesus was born in Bethlehem of
Judea in the days of Herod the king,
behold, there came wise men from the
east to Jerusalem saying, "Where is he
that is born king of the Jews? For we
have seen a star in the east and are
come to worship him."
When Herod the king had heard these
things, he He was troubled and all
Jerusalem with him.
And when he had gathered all the chief
priests and scribes of the people
together, he demanded of them where
Christ should be born. Mhm.
[clears throat] And they said unto him,
"In Bethlehem of Judaea, for thus it is
written by the prophet. Mhm. And thou
Bethlehem and the land of Judah art not
the least among the princes of Judah,
for out of thee shall come a governor
that shall rule my people Israel." Read
verse 8.
And he sent them to Bethlehem and said,
"Go and search diligently for the young
child. And when ye have found him, bring
me word again that I may come and
worship him also." Let's get down and
read verse 13 14.
And when they were departed, behold, the
angel of the Lord appeared to Joseph in
a dream saying, "Arise and take the
young child and his mother and flee into
Egypt. And be thou there until I bring
thee word, for Herod will seek the young
child to destroy him." Okay, so we still
ain't determining when or what year
Jesus was born yet, okay?
Uh read verse
You you read 14, right? No. Read 14.
>> when he arose And when he arose, he took
the young child and his mother by night
and departed into Egypt. And one more
verse, verse 16.
Then Herod, when he saw that he was
mocked of the wise men, was exceeding
wroth and sent forth and slew all the
children that were in Bethlehem and in
the all the coasts thereof from 2 years
old and under according to the time
which he had diligently inquired of the
wise men. [clears throat] Yeah, so
Herod, way back then,
didn't know when Jesus was born or what
year he was born in, and we don't know
in these modern days either.
That That's all I got.
Right. So, we don't know when Jesus was
born. It's not in the scriptures. That's
correct. So, to be saying it's Jesus'
birthday, celebrating Christmas is not
in the scriptures.
All right. Our next one is Time is
fastly ticking. Yes. Our next one,
Danielle um uh Tomorrow Williams wanted
to know
uh what version or year of a King James
Bible should we get?
What version of the KJV, known as the
King James Bible, Brother Julius, should
we get?
You should get
uh the modern
KJV
uh modern English KJV
uh Bible without the Apocrypha.
Without the Apocrypha. The language that
King James spoke was called in 1611 was
called Shakespearean or or early modern
English. You have a early modern, then
you have a middle English, and then you
have the English that we speak today.
So, the 1611
uh that we read uh today in modern
English is predicated off of the early
Shakespearean English or what you call
the King James, the language that King
James spoke, that type of English, which
was early uh modern English. And then
you have middle English come along, and
now we speak modern English. So, now we
don't say, "Thou shalt not kill." You
say, "You shall not kill." But yet we
understand it, "Thou shalt not kill."
So, it's saying the same thing,
you know, so that's what we use,
the
uh modern King James or what you call
the authorized version
um
without the Apocrypha, because that
Apocrypha was added by the Catholics.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on.
Moving on. Cassio Lee wants explanation
about the white throne judgment, or do
we have any Bible lessons on it?
All right. I think you skipped one.
Tomorrow Lee, okay, Danielle Wellington.
Yep, that's the one. Yeah, yeah, okay.
Danielle Wellington wants to know, can
you watch religious movies on TV and
listen to religious music on the
Sabbath?
I would say there's nothing wrong with
listening to the to some nice gospel
music, but I would say on the religious
movies, no.
I've watched some of those movies and
some of their trains come way off the
track and get into some things that have
nothing to do with the Sabbath day.
Remember, the Lord said it's a holy day
and he want us to honor it and respect
it and do it the way he said do it.
Because some of those movies, when you
consider the producers and the writers
who don't even know God, they put stuff
in there that does not pertain to you
keeping the Sabbath day.
So,
I would say just give God all your time
just for that one day.
Listen to you some good music if your
heart desire, but the movies, no, it's
too many writers and producers that have
nothing to do with the word of God.
And that's all I got. On the other days,
you're okay. If Sabbath day, leave
alone.
All right. Moving on to our next one.
Yeah, next one then is Cassio Lee wants
explanation about the white throne
judgment or do we have uh do we have any
uh Bible lessons on it? All right. Guest
caller, you mentioned earlier about the
white throne judgment.
Yeah, well, the whole thing is there's
nothing to explain.
It speaks for itself.
Everyone that was not in the first
resurrection
will be judged at that time.
Just go to Revelation 20th chapter and
read verses 11 and 12.
Okay. Revelation 20 verses 11 and 12
says,
"And I saw a great white throne and him
that sat on it, from whose face the
earth and the heaven fled away. And
there was found no place for them.
And I saw the dead, small and great,
stand before God, and the books were
opened, and another book was opened,
which is the book of life, and the dead
were judged out of those things which
were written in the books according to
their works."
Now, that's pretty plain That's pretty
plain there. What is there to explain
about it?
Mhm. Everyone in the first resurrection,
you're going to stand in the white
throne judgment. You're going to be
judged
out of Bible, the books.
So, all that's simple.
Yeah. It speaks for itself.
All right. And um
these next two questions I think will be
um some short answers, too. So, let's um
deal with these next two and then we'll
conclude the program. Sister Deborah,
what's the next?
Yes, [clears throat] Lexie Amalie asked,
"Is death the only circumstance that
allows someone to remarry?"
Open to the panel.
Go to Deuteronomy 24th chapter.
Deuteronomy 24.
Verses 1 and 2.
Okay. Deuteronomy 24
verses 1 and 2 says,
"When a man hath taken a wife and
married her, and it come to pass that
she find no favor in his eyes because he
has found some uncleanness in her, then
let him write her a bill of divorcement
and give it in in her hand and send her
out of the house.
And when she is departed out of his
house, she may go and be another man's
wife."
That's all that I have to say.
All right. We're going to leave it right
there as we go to our final question of
the evening. What is it, Deborah?
>> Yeah Yes, Robert Dolch says, "Funerals
are common on the Sabbath.
Uh is it violation to attend?"
Indeed, funerals are common on the
Sabbath. Is it a violation to attend?
Guest caller.
There's nothing written in the Bible
that say it is or it is not.
All right.
We're going to leave that final question
of the evening and we're going to say
Sister Deborah, time check.
Yes, the time is 9:03.
All right. 9:03. We want to thank
everybody from all around the world who
tuned in with us this evening and we
want to say that if you submitted a
question and we didn't have a chance to
get to it, don't resubmit it. We will
deal with that question next Wednesday
at the same time. So, until we all come
together again, we say be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
James closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors, and lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil,
for thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
>> night all.